他们所做的事...
what they're doing...
非常危险
it's dangerous.
我求你...
I'm begging you, please...
一定要阻止他们
you've got to stop them.
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
轻点
Quiet.
你要去哪儿?
Where are you going?
快来 跟着我
Come on, follow me.
我们不该上去
We're not supposed to go up there.
我们得为圣餐仪式好好练习
We're supposed to be practicing for communion.
谁在乎圣餐?
Who cares about communion?
我知道Brooks神父藏酒的地方
I know where father brooks keeps the wine.
嘿 你去哪儿?
Hey, where you going?
受害者砸碎彩色玻璃窗掉了下来
Our vic crashed through a stained glass window.
谁报的警?
Who called it in?
Brooks神父
Father brooks.
他还惊魂未定
Little shaken up.
像是个堕落天使
Fallen angel thing.
死者身上没有身份证明
Still no id on the vic.
可能是米迦勒或加百列
(两人都是圣经中提到过的大天使)
Could be a michael or gabriel.
人们说曼哈顿生活艰难
They say it's tough to make it in manhattan.
天堂一定是个残酷的地方
Heaven must be brutal.
是啊
Yeah.
我们还在查失踪人口...
We're still checking missing persons...
和诺斯卑达穆斯(法国星相学家)
and nostradamus.
没有别的目击者?
No other witnesses?
没有
Nope.
制服警员仔细检查了周围地区
没有发现
Unis canvassed the surrounding area and got nothing.
昨晚警区确实接到了一连串电话
The two-seven did receive a bunch of calls last night.
举报非法闯入
Reports of a possible b&E.
另外他们觉得听到了玻璃破碎声
但不确定具体位置
Also, they thought they heard glass breaking, but no particular location.
那其他大楼的外部监视器呢?
What about the external security cameras from other buildings?
拍到屋顶的几部显示上面没人
然后一个戴着巨大翅膀的家伙从天而降
Couple of them show the roof of the church with no one on it, and a guy with big wings falls out of the sky.
我查过了 当时这一带并没有活动
也没有公开的特技表演
I checked, there were no scheduled events in the area, no publicity stunts.
给空管中心打过电话
也没有飞行记录
Called air traffic control, no reports of flyovers.
这家伙真是诡异
This one's just weird.
如果他不是
从降落伞或飞行器上掉下来...
If he didn't fall from some type of parachute or aircraft...
天堂总是有的
there's always heaven.
-=犯罪现场调查纽约篇 CSI:NY=-
第三季 第二十二集
CSI: NY
Season 3 Episode 22
*旧案揭示*
*Cold Reveal*
运走尸体前
Brooks神父想念段祷文
father brooks would like to say a prayer before we move the body.
没问题
Sure.
我马上好了
I'm almost done here.
铁索
Carabiner.
这孩子身上一定还绑过东西
Kid must've been attached to something.
钩子 挽具 翅膀
Hook, harness, wings.
这算是什么? 实习天使?
What are we looking at, some kind of angel in training?
也许他飞过了头 掉下来了
Maybe he overshot a landing and fell.
不管他在干什么
Whatever he was doing...
我觉得他并非意外
I don't think he fell by accident.
绳索是切割过的
This cord's been cut.
整个切口几乎都很整齐
Clean cut's almost all the way through.
蓄意破坏
Sabotage.
没错
Right.
绳索被割后承重能力变弱
加上他的体重造成其全部断裂
The cords were weakened by the cut, and the weight of his body did the rest.
他所剩下的就只有一副翅膀
和一段祷文
All he had left were wings and a prayer.
嘿 Sid
Hey, sid.
Mac派我来的
Mac sent me up here.
听说你复原了一些 嗯…
Said you recovered some, uh...
证据?
whoa, evidence?
是啊
Yeah.
看来年轻的伊卡罗斯(希腊神话中的人物)
飞得离科技天堂太近了
It seems young icarus flew too close to tech heaven.
那个是微型摄影机吗?
Is that a micro video camera?
是的
Yep.
我发现这东西嵌在他的胸口
I found it embedded in his chest.
我认为它原先应该绑在背带的前方
I believe it may have been attached to the front of his harness.
看到了么?
See?
打扰一下 给你
Excuse me.Here you go.
哦 谢谢 Rashida
Oh, thanks, rashida.
不客气
You're welcome.
年轻的伊卡罗斯现在有了新名字
Young icarus now has an alias.
Toby Finch 18岁
Toby finch, 18.
血液中酒精浓度相当高
Blood-alcohol level was quite high.
听起来象是一些小鬼的疯狂表演出了岔子
Sounds like some crazy kid stunt gone wrong.
哦 是啊
Oh, yeah.
一定很恐怖 径直坠落
看着地面越来越近却无力阻止
Must've been horrible, falling, not being able to stop, seeing the ground get closer and closer.
从天堂堕落并非致死原因
His fall from grace didn't kill him.
那死因是什么?
What was cod?
枕骨寰椎分离
Occipito atlantal separation.
他脊柱有两处受到重创
His spine was severed in two places.
撞击地面之前就已经死了
He was dead before he hit the ground.
Sinclair主任
地方检察官为何不起诉Taylor警探?
chief sinclair, why isn't the D.A.Filing charges against detective taylor?
地方检查官对他涉嫌
Clay Dobson一案的调查已经结束
The district attorney's investigation of his involvement with clay dobson was thorough.
没有足够证据以刑事案件起诉
There was not enough evidence to move forward with a criminal case.
一名戴着手铐的犯人从屋顶上坠落
A handcuffed prisoner fell from a rooftop.
Taylor和Dobson曾有宿怨是真的吗?
Isn't it true taylor had a vendetta against dobson?
"宿怨"是个强烈的字眼
"Vendetta" is a strong word.
"追求正义的激情"比较准确
"Passion for justice" is a bit more accurate.
不要忘了Dobson谋杀了至少两名女性
Let's not forget that dobson murdered at least two women.
而Mac Taylor 是一名评价很高的警探
And mac taylor is a highly decorated detective.
这是六个月以来
纽约警察局涉嫌的第三起死亡
This is the third death in the last six months at the hands of the nypd.
你和你的部门怎么能继续忽视这一点?
How can you and the department continue to ignore it?
Sinclair主任 你认为是
Taylor故意让Dobson坠下屋顶的吗?
chief sinclair, do you think taylor let dobson fall off that rooftop?
只有Taylor警探和Clay Dobson
才知道事情的来龙去脉
Only detective taylor and clay dobson know exactly what happened.
但我想向全体市民保证
答案会很快水落石出
But I want to assure the people of this city, the answers are forthcoming.
我会尽一切力量去追查真相
And I will exhaust all the resources of my office to find the truth.
主任 我们什么时候才能知道答案?
Chief, when can we expect those answers?
Gerrard督察 你还有什么别的要说的吗?
Inspector gerrard, do you have anything more to say about this?
我想我们说的已经够多了
We've said enough, I think.
Taylor探长?
Detective taylor?
我是Scotty Valens
Scotty valens.
费城凶杀组
Philadelphia homicide.
我收到你的留言
I got your message.
有关我们的实验室在CODIS中的记录
Something about a codis hit to our lab.
是啊 FBI发现了这个记录
而后移交给了费城警察局
Yeah, the fbi flagged the hit and kicked it down to philly pd.
他们发现这和我们的一个案子有关
They found a connect to one of our jobs.
是10年前一件未被侦破的谋杀案
A ten-year-old murder never solved.
CODIS中的记录
符合你们实验室里的一名女性
The codis hit to your lab was from a female.
我不明白
I don't understand.
我的DNA怎么会跑的CODIS里去的?
How did my dna end up in codis?
Adam做PCR测试
检查你是否感染HIV时录入的
It happened when adam conducted the pcr test to determine your hiv status.
但在进行PCR测试前
我记得把二次取样放在台子上的
But before I ran the pcr test, I remember setting the secondary sample down on the counter.
我不知道 也许是实验室技术人员...
I don't know, maybe, like, a lab tech...
意外收起来的
accidentally picked it up.
解释了费城凶杀组
在CODIS找到吻合记录的原因
Which explains why philly homicide got a hit in codis.
凶杀组?
Homicide?
Stella 一件谋杀案的证据上
找到了你的DNA
Stella, your dna was found on evidence connected with a murder.
那不可能
That's impossible.
这件外套看起来眼熟吗?
Does this coat look familiar?
不
No.
想象它没那么脏 干净一点
Picture it less dirty, faded.
之前从没见过 警探
I've never seen the coat before, detective.
我们在现场找到一条裙子
There's a blouse we found at the scene.
我们真的要这样一张张来
让你分析我眼睛的变化吗?
Are we really gonna do this one picture at a time while you analyze every shifty eye move?
没错
Yeah.
我们就是要这么干
That's really how we're gonna do it.
就让我看一下案卷吧
Just let me take a look at the case file.
你也许是名警探 但同时也是嫌犯
You may be a detective, but you're also a suspect.
我是个能帮上你忙的警察
I'm a cop who can help you.
你的部门在找上我以前已经走进了死胡同
Your department has been at a dead end until you got to me.
你发现证据的时候我并不在费城
我在纽约上警察学院
I wasn't in philly when you found your evidence, I was here in new york attending the police academy.
那么何不利用我们法医实验室的资源呢?
So what do you say we use the resources of our forensic lab?
让别的人看看这案子 看看是否
有与此证据相关的联系--有关纽约的联系
Bring on some fresh eyes, see if there's a connection-- a new york connection-- to this evidence.
我们认为一名年轻女子死了
We think a young woman is dead.
97年3月
March '97.
工人在土里发现了血衣和小刀
Workers found the bloody clothes and knife buried in the dirt.
衣服是在朝费城方向的
费城高速公路的南面找到的
The clothes were on the south side of the philadelphia turnpike headed towards philly.
没有目击者 没有失踪人口报告 只有这件证据
No witnesses, no missing persons report filed, just this evidence.
刀上没有指纹 但衬衣上有三处切口
No prints on the knife, but the blouse had three cuts in it.
衣服上的血大部分是女性的
Most of the blood on the clothes was female.
但也有一些男性的DNA
But there was some male dna.
当然 我们也发现了你的血迹
Of course, we found traces of your blood as well.
上面说衬衣的袖口上粘有显影药水
Now it says here that the blouse had photo developing chemicals on the cuffs.
是的 我们认为死者可能是个摄影师
Yeah, we think the victim may have been a photographer.
外套上有氯丁二烯橡胶
凡士林和荧光白油漆
Traces of neoprene and vaseline, iridescent white paint were found on the coat.
那有很多不同的用途
It has a lot of different uses.
让我看看化学物质报告
Let me see this chemical report.
氯丁二烯橡胶 凡士林和荧光油漆
So iridescent paint, vaseline and neoprene.
是橡胶 对吗?
It's rubber, right?
你在想什么?
Mm-hmm, mm-hmm.What are you thinking?
十年前 这三种物质
在曼哈顿某处占重要地位
Well, ten years ago, all three of these materials were featured prominently in one place in manhattan.
"街道博物馆"里的一件艺术品
A piece of art at the museo del barrio.
你当时在那?
You were there?
不 不 我只是记得在报纸上看过
No, no, I just remember reading about it in the paper.
你说这名死者是摄影师
You said that your vic was a photographer.
也许是她在拍照的时候靠在了那上面
蹭到了这些物质
Maybe she brushed up or leaned against it and picked up the trace while she was taking photos.
好吧 我去给报社打个电话
看他们的存档里有没有线索
All right, I'm gonna put a call into the newspapers, see if they have anything in their archives.
谢谢 Danny
Thanks, danny.
知道吗 我们应该查查纽约的失踪人口
You know, we should check new york's missing persons,
看看有没有和博物馆有关的人失踪了
see if there's anyone associated with the museum who may have gone missing.
我们?
We?
我可没在找搭档啊
I ain't looking for a partner here.
想想看 我可是你唯一的线索
Well, consider me your only lead.
嘿 Mac 我检查了
背带上蹦极绳的剩余部分
Hey, mac, I took a look at the remnants of the bungee cords that were on the harness.
切口是由复合刀刃造成的
The cuts were made by a combo edge blade.
大多数随身小折刀都是这样
Standard in most pocket knives.
那可能是这个阴谋的来源
That may be our source of sabotage.
绳子上的指纹呢?
Any luck with prints on the cord?
还在处理 另外在等
从他凉鞋底上采取的物质的报告
Still working on that and waiting on trace I collected from the soles of his sandals.
我从受害者翅膀上的发射器里
恢复了部分图像
Hey, I recovered partial images from a transmitter I found in the vic's wings.
有些东西你得看看
There's something you should see.
阻止你的朋友们
Stop your friends.
我们正在死去 但没人来阻止这一切
因为没人在乎
We're dying, and no one's going to stop us because no one cares.
这可不是Toby
This isn't toby.
是啊 但这是这整个故事的开始
Yeah, but this is the beginning of the whole story.
我要成为下一个互联网百万富翁超胆侠!
I want to be the next $100,000 internet daredevil!
这是同一个女孩吗?
Is this the same girl?
没错 这是Jessica
Yeah, this is jessica.
来吧 把它点上!
Here we go, light it up!
她就是这样被毁容的
Here's how she became disfigured.
等等 哇 哇 哇!
Wait, whoa, whoa, whoa!
她放下酒杯的时候
一些酒撒到了衣服上 着了火
When she downed the shot, she spilled some of the alcohol on her coat, and it caught fire.
你从哪找到的?
where'd you find this?
一个叫"互联网超胆侠"的网站
On a website called internetdaredevil.Com.
他们正在比赛
录下最疯狂大胆的表演
They're running a contest to see who can get the craziest stunt recorded on video.
现在你要看到的就是Toby的翅膀上的
发射器记忆卡里被我恢复的东西
Now, what you're about to see is from the memory card I recovered on the transmitter in toby's wings.
我要成为下一个互联网百万富翁超胆侠!
I want to be the next $100,000 internet daredevil!
他喝醉了 试图完成一些疯狂表演
He was drunk, trying to pull off some crazy stunt.
这表明Toby是从某处起飞
最后掉进了教堂
It appears toby was launched from somewhere and ended up at the church.
分析一下录像
Analyze the video.
地表 飞行速度 气温--
看看能否找到他的起始点
Landmarks, run velocity, air temp-- see if you can find his starting poinT.
网页呢?
What about this website?
它激励孩子们伤害自己
It's encouraging kids to hurt themselves.
肯定不合法
That can't be legal.
比赛可不是犯罪
Well, contests aren't a crime.
愚蠢和缺乏判断力也不是
Neither is stupidity or bad judgment.
在Toby的案子中
我们有证据表明有人割了蹦极绳
In toby's case, we have evidence someone cut the bungee cord.
也许那人不希望他赢得大奖
Maybe that someone didn't want him to win the grand prize.
Danny 你有什么发现?
Danny, what do you got?
发现一张1997年3月30日照片
登在 "街道博物馆"的"悲伤之墙"上
Found a photo expos?on the "sorrowful wall" from the museo del barrio march 30, 1997.
血衣被发现后的一天
The day after the bloody clothes were found.
照片是一个叫Erin Yates的人拍的
Photo byline was an erin yates.
还有这个--把胶卷交给展览会之后
他们就再也没有她的消息了
And get this-- after she handed in the film on the exhibit, paper never heard from her again.
她可能是那个受害人吗?
Could she be your vic?
有可能
Could be.
编辑把她留下的东西送了来
The editor sent over her box of belongings that she left behind.
被水泡过
There's water damage.
地下室水管爆裂造成的
Something about a pipe busting in the basement.
媒体通行证
Press pass.
不认识她
Don't know her.
发现若干胶卷
最后一卷标着1997年3月27日
Found a bunch of rolls of film and the last one dated is march 27, 1997,
也就是你们发现血衣的两天前
which is two days before you found the bloody clothes.
不知道她为什么没把胶卷洗出来
I wonder why she never developed the film.
也许Erin拍了不该拍的东西
Maybe erin took photographs of something she shouldn't have.
都是同一个人么?
These all the same guy?
看起来好像是
Looks like it.
可是没法看到脸部的清晰图像
Can't get a clear image of the face, though.
底片被水严重损坏
The negatives were severely damaged from the water.
不管这个人是谁
看起来Erin Yates当时在监视他
But whoever this guy is, looks like erin yates was watching him.
你是说假扮Erin Yates的那个人
You mean whoever's posing as erin yates.
查了社会保障记录 发现
真正的Erin 15年前就在睡梦中死去了
Ran the social-- turns out the real erin died in her sleep 15 years ago.
那就是说我们的摄影师盗用了她的身份?
So our photographer stole her identity?
她在躲藏什么东西
She's hiding from something.
Stell 你还好吧?
You okay, stell?
哦 不
Uh, no.
我不好
No, I'm not.
那是你 Stella
That's you, stella.
她出现在你的警校毕业典礼上
She was at your academy graduation.
我是说 Erin Yates 或者不管是谁
拍了你的那张照片
I mean, erin yates, or whoever she is, took that picture of you.
你是那卷胶卷上唯一的一个毕业生
And you're the only graduate on that roll of film.
我不认识Erin
也不知道她为什么要拍这些照片
I don't know erin, and I have no idea why she took these pictures.
我在这儿收集的所有线索都指向你
Every dot I connect here leads back to you.
我无法给出你要的答案 Valens警探
I don't have the answers you're looking for, detective valens.
相信我 我真的希望可以
Believe me, I wish I did.
你在隐藏什么 Stella?
What are you hiding, stella?
没什么
Nothing.
我什么也没隐藏
I'm not hiding anything.
听着 Valens 如果她说不知道
那就是不知道
Look, valens, if she says she doesn't know, she don't know.
我同意让你参与这个案子
因为你是个警察
I agreed to let you work this case 'cause you're a cop.
我一直试图按照你们的方法办事
I've been trying to go along with the way you guys work.
显然 是我错了
Clearly, my mistake.
我几小时后回来
I'll be back in a couple hours.
如果你还是不说
我们可能就得按费城的方法办了
If you still ain't talking, maybe we do it my way in philly.
怎么回事啊?
What's going on?
Stella 看着我
Stella, look at me.
你现在有什么头绪?
What's haunting you?
我不知道 Danny 这就是问题所在
I don't know, danny, that's the problem.
我不知道
I don't know.
噢 讨厌 三角数学
Oh, yuck, trigonometry.
是啊 正弦定理
Yeah, the rule of sines.
我们想要找出Toby Finch起飞的确切地址
We are trying to figure out the exact place where toby finch took flight.
从他起飞后所拍摄的影像长度
Video footage from where he was launched.
右边的这栋楼看起来
是Wexler大楼 对吗?
This building on the right looks to be the wexler building, okay?
在左边 Hannaford分部
On the left, hannaford arms.
计算两者之间的距离--得出搜查范围
Calculate the distance between the two-- come up with a search zone.
他是从这块区域的某处起飞的
He was launched somewhere in this area.
那么这样会有 多少?
So that's gotta be, what?
200±50的大楼屋顶需要检查?
200 rooftops plus or minus 50?
低于12楼以及
高于15楼的大楼都可以排除
We can eliminate every building shorter than 12 stories, but we can also eliminate every building higher than 15 stories.
是啊
Uh-huh, yeah.
粗略估计还剩下120个可能的屋顶
That leaves us with roughly 120 possible rooftops.
嘿...
Hey...
别看着我们--困难的部分我们都搞定了
Don't look at us-- we did the hard part.
你们三个看上去不是很乐观啊
you three don't look very optimistic.
受害者的起飞地点是个大大的未知数
The victim's launch site is a big unknown.
气质联用分析结果显示他的鞋底有石油
和大理石的痕迹 和普通屋顶材料一致
But gcms results from the soles of his shoes indicate traces of oil and marble, consistent with common roofing materials.
可是 这可以帮助我们缩小搜寻条件
因为屋顶不都用相同的沥青混合物
However, it could help us narrow our search criteria, because not all rooftops have the same asphalt mixture.
听起来要打很多电话还要跑不少路
Sounds like a lot of phone calls and footwork.
嘿 等一下 Sheldon
Hey, wait a minute, sheldon.
如果找到石油 就意味着
房顶最近才铺好 可能还产生热量
If you found oil, it means the roof was recently paved and could still be generating heat.
对
Right.
因为那些石油还是液体
Because the oil was still liquid.
还没有冷却下来
It hadn't cooled.
正确
Right.
在搜查范围内通过测量屋顶温度的差别
我们或许就能找到精确的地址了
We might be able to pinpoint an exact location by measuring the temperature differential of roof surfaces in our search zone.
太棒了
That's great, yeah.
你要怎么做?
How do you do that?
不要再开远了
nothing so far.
我们朝北边看看
Let's head further north.
遵命
Okay, we'll do that.
我们方向向北
We'll go further north.
出发
Here you go.
转向270度...
Coming about at 270...
空中霸王K-E-B-99
呼叫Laguardia塔台 回话
this is skymaster kilo, echo, bravo, 99-er to laguardia tower.Come in.
下面的是什么地方?
What's below us?
那是Chase-Whittly大楼 警探
That's the chase-whittly building, detective.
Hawkes 告诉Flack
尽快抵达Chase-Whittly大楼
hawkes, tell flack to get access to the chase-whittly buildinG.A.S.A.P.
可以了
We're good.
收到
Roger that.
有空吗 Mac?
Do you have a minute, mac?
警局要进行内部调查
The police department is going forward with an internal investigation.
你是说检察官没证据证实是我把Dobson
推下了大楼 但是纽约警局却不确定?
So you're telling me the D.A.Has no evidence that suggests I tossed dobson off that building, but nypd isn't sure?
事情没那么简单 Mac
It's not as simple as that, mac.
是的 我也没以为简单
No, I don't imagine it is.
这和警局有关
This is about the police department.
你的意思是 你和Sinclair
感受到些许的媒体压力
What you mean is that you and sinclair felt a little media pressure,
而为了警局
你们不准备为我辩护
and for the sake of the department, you're not going to come to my defense.
我猜想 这事该不会跟私人关系有关吧
I suppose I shouldn't take that personally.
警局需要对市民负责
The department has an obligation to the people of this city.
你以前是很有效率的
You used to walk the beat, stan.
当42大街满是妓女和毒品贩子的时候
你在那巡逻
You patrolled 42nd street when it was nothing but hookers and drug dealers
你和其他不辞辛劳的警察一点一滴
把那里清理干净 变成今天的模样
and little by little you and a dozen other hardworking cops cleaned it up, made it what it is today.
你到底想说什么 Taylor?
What's your point, taylor?
我只是很好奇
Well, I was just wondering.
当你逮捕那些坏蛋
把他们铐起来的时候
When you were making all those arrests, locking up bad guys,
你有没有想过有朝一日你会忙着拍
警长的马屁 不记得怎样才能做个警察?
were you imagining a day when you'd be so busy kissing the chief of detectives' ass you wouldn't remember what it was like to be a cop?
你个狗娘养的
You son of a bitch.
你不能这么说我
I don't deserve that.
我在这是因为...
You know, I'm here because...
没必要解释 督察
you don't have to explain it, inspector.
我明白 你只是个傀儡而已
I get it; you're just the puppet.
我会把我的案子交给那个幕后黑手的
I'll take my case to the badge that pulls the strings.
这些是同一人?
These all the same guy?
看上去是
Looks like it.
Valens 怎么了?
Valens, what's up?
是啊 你在哪?
Yeah, where are you at?
好 你知道吗?
All right, well, you know what?
就呆在那 我去找你
Stay right there, 'cause I'm gonna come grab you.
我找到一个地址
I got an address.
那是我的前夫
That's my ex-husband.
Garth
Garth.
真的?
Really?
你能告诉我们上哪儿找他吗?
Well, can you tell us where we can find him?
有些问题要问他
Got some questions for him.
不知道
No.
上次见面是10年前
某天突然没有回家
Saw him last ten years ago; just didn't come home one day.
你提交失踪人口报告了吗?
You file a missing persons' report?
我有想过
但是Garth之前也失踪过几星期
I thought about it, but then garth had gone missing for weeks at a time before.
我只是觉得某天他会屁颠屁颠回来的
I just figured he'd bring his trifling butt back home at some point.
你有Garth的东西吗 比如旧剃刀
也许一些毛发或者衣服?
You wouldn't happen to have anything of garth's, like an old razor, maybe a lock of hair or, um, clothes?
没有 他所有的东西我都扔了
No, I got rid of every trace of him.
听着 伙计们 我拥有一个收养家庭
Look, fellas, I run a foster home.
政府会给我一笔钱 就这样
The government gives me a certain amount of money.That's it.
他离开后 留给我们的钱就多点
I mean, with him gone, more for the rest of us.
你认识这个女的吗?
Do you know this woman?
看上去不太眼熟
No, she doesn't look familiar.
这是谁?
Well, who's this?
啊 那是Mindy Mindy Sanchez
Ah, that's mindy, mindy sanchez.
她过去 过去住在这儿
Yeah, she used to, she used to live here.
知道她现在在哪吗?
You know where she is now?
不知道
No clue.
她离家出走了
She ran away.
某天早上起来 她就不见了
Woke up one morning and she was gone.
最后一个问题
You know, one last thing.
你认识一个叫Stella Bonasera的人吗?
Do you know a stella bonasera?
认识
Yeah.
Stella
Stella.
她曾是我收养的孩子
She was one of my foster kids.
大家都忘不了Stella
No one could ever forget stella.
所以我们认为Mindy就是Erin
So we think mindy is erin.
是那个项坠
that's the locket.
这能解释为何
我的DNA会弄到那些衣服上
The locket explains how my dna got on those clothes.
Mindy和我一起发了誓
Mindy and I made a pact.
一辈子都是朋友
Friends forever and ever.
你告诉我你不认识这个姑娘?
You're telling me you didn't recognize this girl?
你的结拜姐妹?
Your blood sister?
那个时候的确没认出来
No, I didn'T.
记者证照片上的项坠也不眼熟吗?
And the locket in the press pass photo didn't look familiar?
噢 拜托 我怎么可能认得出来?
Oh, please, how could I possibly recognize this?
你发了誓
却不记得跟你结拜的那个人?
You make this pact and you don't remember the one item that bonds you together?
Mindy把那个项坠带走了
Mindy took the locket with her.
除了里面的东西 这个项坠
没有任何令人注目或者有特色的地方
There's nothing memorable or distinctive about this locket, except for what's inside of it.
孩子分享秘密 Stella
Kids share secrets, stella.
也许Mindy告诉过你些什么
而你答应帮她保守秘密
Maybe mindy told you something, something you promised to keep quiet.
你要说的是什么 Valens?
What are you getting at, valens?
如果那个未知男性DNA是Garth Bennett的
而未知女性是Mindy Sanchez
If garth bennett is our unknown male dna and mindy sanchez is the unknown female,
你养父要杀你的好友一定是有原因的
there's got to be a reason why your foster dad wanted to kill your best friend.
Sinclair主任
Chief sinclair.
你有10分钟 Mac
You've got ten minutes, mac.
我想要你撤销内部事务调查
I'd like you to drop your internal affairs investigation.
一个嫌疑犯从20层的高楼坠下
而当时只有你和他在一起
A suspect falls from a 20-story building and the only other person on that roof is you.
如果不作询问
这个部门就会显得很不负责
It would be irresponsible of this department to not ask a few questions.
我已经接受过询问了
The questions have been asked.
检察官对答案很满意
The D.A.Is satisfied with the answers.
你和我都知道这么做是为什么
You and I both know what this is.
你屈服于媒体压力
而我成了你个人政治利益的牺牲品
You're caving to media pressure, and I'm being made an example for your own political gain.
你是在暗示我是为了一己私欲?
So you're implying that I have a personal agenda here?
这么说还算客气的了 是的
That's the polite way of putting it, yeah.
那么就不要客气了 让我说清楚
Well, let's stop being polite and let me make something perfectly clear.
保持警局的正直和形象是我的责任
The integrity and image of the police department are my responsibility.
当一位警官涉嫌一名嫌犯的死亡
我就必须有所交待
When an officer is involved in the death of a suspect, I have to answer for that.
说得还真像局长候选人啊
Spoken like a true candidate for commissioner.
也许因为你每天舒舒服服的坐在实验室里
You know, maybe because you sit in the comfort of a lab every day,
你接触不到市民对警局的看法
you're out of touch with the public's perception of the police department.
他们认为我们临驾于法律之上
做错任何事只要暗箱操作就可以了
See, they believe that we are above the law and any wrongdoing is just swept under the carpet.
而你要以我的事业为代价
主持这次的控诉来改变市民的看法?
And you're leading the charge to change that perception at the expense of my career?
Mac 我现在站的立场和你逮捕
Dean Truby警探时是一样的
I'm taking the same stand you took, mac, when you arrested detective dean truby.
是啊 我猜当你没站在警徽的角度时
就有点不一样了
Yeah, I guess it's a little bit different when you're on the other side of the badge.
如果你没做错什么 就没什么好担心的
If you didn't do anything wrong, you have nothing to worry about.
我是最后一个
I'm the last one.
其他曾受雇于Giuliani市长的人不是
被迫退休就是晋升到没有实权的行政工作
Everyone else hired under mayor giuliani you've either forced into retirement or promoted to powerless administrative jobs.
谢谢你保留我到最后
Good thing you saved me for last.
你会面对一场难以忘怀的抗争
You're about to face a fight you won't forget.
你好?
hello?
嘿 Adam
能把那张定格照片发到我手机上吗?
Hey, adam, can you send the freeze-frame to my phone?
好
Yeah.
我 我这就来
I, uh, I got it right here.
发过来了
It's on its way.
同样的两栋大楼
Same two buildings.
Toby Finch是个人体弹弓
Toby finch was a human slingshot.
蹦极绳是系在那里和那里的
而他大概是从这...
The bungees were attached there and there, and he was released...
被弹出去的
from right about here.
那就可以解释他的水平飞行和颈部损伤了
That explains his horizontal flight and neck injury.
是的
Yeah.
冲击力瞬间折断他的颈部
The force immediately snapped his neck.
伸展那些蹦极绳要花很大的力气
It would take a lot of strength to extend those bungee cords.
如果被系到那些柱子上
他的脚是不可能着地的
If he were attached to those pillars up there, his feet wouldn't be on the ground.
那么他是怎么回到这儿呢?
So how'd he get back here?
起艇绞车和一个朋友帮了点小忙
With a little help from a boat winch and a friend.
我还发现了数码照相机的电池包装
但是和受害者那找到的不一样
I also found some battery packaging consistent with a digital camera, but not compatible with the one we found on our vic.
还有别人拍下来了?
Somebody else got this on film?
还发现了另一组脚印...
Now, found another set of footprints...
在这里
here.
看上去象女性的高跟鞋
Looked to be a female's high heels.
好吧 Hawkes 去调查吧
All right, hawkes, run with it.
Mac 如果局里决定进行内部调查
我就得去回答问题
You know, mac, if the, uh, department decides to go through with their internal investigation, I'm gonna have to answer questions.
我知道的就是到楼顶时你告诉我的
All I know is what you told me when I got up to the top.
就像我告诉检察官的
我没有把Clay Dobson推下楼
Like I told the D.A., I did not toss clay dobson off that roof.
这次的调查只是场政治表演
This investigation is nothing but a big political show.
是啊
Yeah.
无论如何 媒体清楚这个故事 等他们
不愿再听时 你的说辞可就不管用了 Mac
Regardless, the media's soaking the story up, and by the time they're done with it, your word may not be good enough, mac.
Dobson!
把手举起来 跪下
Put your hands in the air and drop to your knees.
现在!
Now!
你说得没错--关于眼睛的事
You were right-- what you said about the eyes.
我希望她们看着
I wanted them to look.
我希望被我杀死的那些女孩知道
--知道她们最后看到的是我的脸
I wanted those girls I killed to know-- to know that my face was the last thing they were ever gonna see.
闭嘴
Shut uP.
跪下 把手放在头后
Drop to your knees, put your hands behind your head.
快做!
Do it!
你要怎么做 朝我开枪?
What are you gonna do, shoot me?
我都没有武器
I don't even have a weapon.
如果我死了 也要拉你陪葬
if I'm going, I'm taking you with me.
他是被铐上的!
He's cuffed!
那是你最后一次
见到你的朋友Toby 对吗?
That was the last time you saw your friend toby alive, wasn't it?
你能关掉吗?
Can you just turn it off?
我不知道Toby出了什么事
I don't know anything about what happened toby.
你知道 T.J.--Toby做人体弹弓的时候
你就在楼顶上
Yes, you do, T.J.-- You were on the roof when toby was playing human slingshot.
你录了下来 然后上传到一个网站上
You videotaped it, and you downloaded it to a web site.
你们逮到你了 孩子
We got you, kid.
你匿名在学校图书馆的电脑上上传的
You submitted it anonymously from one of the campus library computers,
但是你没想到的是在你图书馆卡背后的
黑色磁条上储存的信息
but what you didn't think about was the information stored on that little black strip on the back of your library card.
T.J. Lindmark 地址 学号 最近的活动
T.J.Lindmark, address, student I.D.Number, recent activity.
我不知道你是怎么想的 但是...
I don't know what you're thinking, but...
我会告诉你我是怎么想的
I'll tell you what I'm thinking.
我们在楼顶找到了11号鞋的足印
并不属于Toby 还有被割蹦极绳上的指纹
We got size-11-tread prints on a rooftop that are not toby's, fingerprints on a cut bungee cord,
而且证据显示蹦极绳是被
随身的小折刀切断的
and evidence that that cord was cut by a pocketknife.
我没有切断蹦极绳
I didn't cut the bungee cord.
我才刚知道它被割断了
I didn't even know it was cut until just now.
我以为Toby的事是个意外
I thought what happened to toby was an accident.
好吧 也许是拍视频的女孩做的
Okay, so maybe the girl who videotaped the whole thing, maybe she did it.
不是
No.
不是 Toby的女朋友绝不会那样做
No, toby-toby's girl would never do that.
Toby的女朋友有名字吗?
Toby's girl have a name?
Amy Newmer
Amy newmer.
她爱Toby
She loved toby.
我可以发誓 没人割断那绳子
I swear to you, nobody cut that cord.
我们只是上楼顶找乐子 试试那个弹射装置
Toby穿了那件傻呼呼的天使服装
We went on the roof to have fun, to take a ride on the slingshot contraption, and toby showed up in that goofy angel outfit.
你醉得太厉害了 伙计
You're too drunk, man.
我不知道
I don't know.
很明显 他是...
And it was obvious he was...
他喝了很多
he was drinking.
当那根蹦极绳断裂时 我和Amy都吓坏了
When that bungee cord snapped, me and amy freaked.
我不会杀死最好的朋友
I wouldn't kill my best friend.
你把视频放到了网站上
You downloaded that video to a web site.
10万元奖励最具胆量视频
$100,000 prize for the most daring video.
实况录下年轻人的死亡
Young kid's death caught on tape.
听起来就象赢定了
Sounds like a winner to me.
我把视频放上网站是为了Toby!
I put that video on the web site for toby!
他整天都说 要成为网络名人
That's all he ever talked about, was being an internet celebrity.
一位虚拟空间的明星
An e-lebrity.
你知道有多少孩子想一夜成名吗?
You know how many kids have gone from being nobodies to stardom overnight?
我是为了他 献给Toby的礼物
因为那就是他想要的
I did it for him, in tribute to toby, because that's what he would have wanted.
我认为不是T.J.割断了绳子
I don't think T.J.Severed that rope.
那会是谁?
Then who did?
我们需要恢复发射器里剩余的图象
We need to recover the rest of the images from that transmitter.
总有人割断了绳子
Somebody cut that bungee.
一定是在Toby戴上那套装备后
Had to be after toby got into that harness.
谢罪礼物
peace offering.
我收到了费城送来的证据
I had the evidence sent up from philly.
在费城 我们也有法医
We have forensic scientists in philadelphia, too.
听着 我无意冒犯 也相信
你们的工作人员都很称职
Look, I'm not trying to insult anyone, and I'm sure that everyone in your department is quite capable.
只是 也许我能解释某些他们无法解释的事
It's just that I might be able to explain something that they can'T.
也许我能解释某些突兀独立的证据
Evidence without context for them might mean something to me.
好吧 Stella 你来处理
Okay, stella, you're driving.
用你喜欢的方式
The way you like it.
你带头
Lead on.
行 很好
Okay, fine.
你们的人有列举这个烧伤的可能起因吗?
What do your people list as probable causes for this burn here?
有许多种可能性
There's a lot of possibilities.
好
Okay.
这个图案又怎么说?
How about this pattern here?
是的 我们查看过
Yeah, we looked at that.
是
Yeah.
“一致于宽锯齿木梳
胶片的锯齿链边角 珠宝..."
"Consistent with tips "of a wide-toothed comb, sprocket pattern of film, jewelry..."
还有另外10种可能性
there's ten other possible possibles.
哪种东西比较特别?
Something stand out?
是的 锯齿链边角
Yeah, sprocket pattern.
Garth Bennett
曾是一家老剧院的电影放映员
Garth bennett was a projectionist at a revival theater.
快点
Come on.
我们走
Let's go.
那个芭蕾女演员叫什么名字?
What's the ballerina's name again?
Victoria Page
Victoria page.
Stella 安静点
Stella, be quiet.
你会给我们惹来麻烦的
You're going to get us in trouble.
发现什么了吗?
you find something?
是的
Yeah.
感受一下温度
Feel the heat.
动脉血喷射轨迹
arterial spray.
这屋里发生过谋杀
A murder happened in this room.
有人重新粉刷过
And someone painted over it.
这比擦除血迹更容易
Easier than wiping it down.
似乎这就是你们的第一犯罪现场
looks like this is your primary crime scene.
管辖权从费城移交到纽约警局
Jurisdiction just shifted from philly to the nypd.
外套证实了受害者在这个房间里
The jacket puts our vic in this room.
Valens?
小指短了一截
Short pinky.
Marilyn Bennett
Marilyn bennett.
你清理了犯罪现场
You cleaned up the crime scene.
你的手印就在墙上
Your handprint was right up there on the wall.
沾满了血
In blood.
和你的完全吻合 Marilyn
It's a perfect match to you, marilyn.
发生了什么事?
What happened?
你发现了Mindy和Garth的事 决心杀了他们?
You find mindy and garth and decide to kill them?
因为我们还没找到他
'Cause we haven't been able to find him.
我没杀任何人
I didn't kill anybody.
对 但你不也说过...
Yeah, but what was it you said?
他所有的东西我都扔了
I got rid of every trace of him.
你没在开玩笑吧?
You weren't kidding, huh?
我没杀任何人
I didn't kill anybody.
你说起来就象你真的相信
You really say that like you believe it.
我是说 已经有段日子了 所以...
I mean, it's been a while, so...
我想在你的脑海里已变成了事实
over time I guess it becomes the truth in your mind.
那就是事实
It is the truth.
我不是凶手
I'm not a murderer.
我们提取了你的DNA
会拿去和凶器上的比对
We swabbed you for dna, and we're going to test that against the murder weapon.
以及你丢在费城路边的衣服
And the clothes that you dumped on the side of the road in philadelphia.
你干嘛不告诉我整个经过 就现在?
Okay, so, why don't you just tell me your story, right now?
我没杀任何人
I didn't kill anybody.
你要走了?
You heading out?
现在是你的案子了
Your case now.
怎么 你有发现了?
What, you find something?
放映室墙上找到的
喷溅动脉血迹的DNA结果出来了...
Dna came back on the arterial blood spatter, from the projection booth wall...
属于男性
male.
和高速公路边证物的DNA一致
Same dna that was on the turnpike evidence.
既然Garth Bennett已失踪近10年...
And since garth bennett's been missing for almost ten years...
很可能是他的
could be his.
当然 我们没找到他的尸体
Of course, we don't have his body.
那Marilyn呢?
And what about marilyn?
衣服不是她的尺寸
Clothes weren't her size.
她的DNA不在外套 衬衫或刀上
No evidence of her dna on the coat, blouse or knife.
如果她没杀丈夫 为何要清理犯罪现场?
So, why'd she clean up the crime scene, if she didn't kill her husband?
也许她在保护某个人
Maybe she was protecting someone.
现场还有第三人的DNA我们没找到主人
There is that third dna donor that we haven't identified yet.
Erin Yates 又名Mindy Sanchez
Erin yates, aka mindy sanchez.
她从看护中心逃跑 用了死亡女子的身份
She runs away from foster care and uses a dead woman's identity.
很难找到她
She's gonna be tough to find.
有消息通知我
Keep me posted.
我会的
Will do.
调查这些旧案时 有件事我一直不习惯
You know, one thing I never get used to about working these cold jobs.
什么?
What's that?
它们会唤醒尘封的过去
They stir up the past.
你多保重 警探
You take care of yourself, detective.
你也保重
You do the same.
我把Toby Finch相机里
剩余的图象都恢复了
I recovered the rest of the images from toby finch's camera.
他的朋友们以为他会是下一个人体投弹
但他另有计划
His friends thought he was gonna be the next human slingsho but he had other plans.
看一下
Take a look.
我用翅膀来当滑翔机翼
I got the same wingspan as a hang glider.
只需要足够的高度和动力 就能借用
曼哈顿地平线产生的上升暖气流
I just need enough height and momentum so I can work the updraft and thermal lifts created by manhattan's skyline.
一旦满足条件...
And once I reach them...
就解放了
release.
好吧
Okay.
他自己割的
He did it himself.
他割断了蹦极绳
He cut the bungee cords.
他指望首次前冲速度能超过绳子的强度
He was counting on the velocity of his first forward swing to overcome the strength of the cords.
以为一旦他跳下去 它们就会断开
He thought they would break as soon as he was launched,
但绳子强度很高 反弹力折断了他的脖子
要了他的命
but the strength of the cords held and the force of the recoil snapped his neck, killing him.
他落地前就死了
He was dead weight before he even landed.
唯一的罪行就是Toby Finch错误的野心
the only crime here was toby finch's misdirected ambition.
就现在 准备起飞
Right here, prepare for takeoff!
开始!
Here we go!
- 准备--三 二 一...
- 互联网超胆侠
- Ready-- three, two, one... - internet daredevil.
找谁?
yes?
Victoria Page?
Victoria page?
我是...
I'M...
Stella Bonasera
stella bonasera.
我没见过你 自从...
I haven't seen you since...
我从警校毕业后
my graduation from the academy.
但你..
But you were...
那时叫Erin Yates
erin yates back then.
请进
Come in.
你怎么找到我的?
How did you find me?
Victoria Page
Victoria page.
红舞鞋
The red shoes.
我一直在...
I've been, uh...
调查这个案子 一直追查到老戏院
working this case that ended up at an old revival movie house.
就是Garth每周六带我们去的那家
The same one that garth took us to every saturday.
我希望有一天能象她一样跳舞
Someday I want to dance like her.
然后他会带你出去
Then he would take you away.
去放映室
To t projection booth.
他强奸了你 是吗?
He did things to you, didn't he?
Stella 不是这样的
Stella, this is a mistake.
几年以后 我冷静了下来想...
Years later, I put it all together...
记得我们坐在那里
remembering us sitting there.
他是如何轻叩你的肩膀
How he would tap you on the shoulder.
那部电影是我们的救命稻草
That movie was our escape.
你从那个噩梦中逃开以拯救自己
And you ran away from that nightmare to save yourself.
同时也救了我
And to save me.
你清楚如果你离开了 他们会把我送走
You knew that if you left, that they would send me away.
我再也不用面对Garth
And I would never have to deal with garth.
我知道他做了什么
I know what he did.
那一定在时刻折磨你
It must have haunted you.
那就是你杀他的原因
And that's why you killed him.
Stella 我没有 也不可能杀死任何人
stella, I didn't, and I couldn't kill anyone.
Marilyn为你清理了犯罪现场 Mindy
Marilyn cleaned up the crime scene for you, mindy.
还记得有几个晚上她为Garth送晚饭吗?
Remember how she used to bring garth dinner some nights?
也许她看到你离开
Maybe she saw you leave.
也许她知道原因
Maybe she knew why.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
我们在费城高速公路边
发现了你埋掉的血衣
We found your bloody clothes on the side of the philly turnpike, where you buried them.
不 我不在那里
No, I wasn't there.
也许不是Mindy或Erin 而是Victoria Page
Maybe not as mindy or erin, but as victoria page.
你在华盛顿特区找了份工作
You had a job lined up in washington, D.C.
在你复仇之后 你直接南下
After you took your revenge, you headed south.
这就是你来这里的原因吗?
Is that why you're here?
来逮捕我?
To arrest me?
如果是几个月前 我会说"是"
A few months ago, I would have said yes.
但生活很奇怪
But life is strange.
我发现生活中有许多灰色区域
I found that it has these gray areas.
有时不是你选择了地狱
而是地狱选择了你
Sometimes you don't choose your own hell, it's chosen for you.
你只是做了该做的事 为了生存
And you do what you need to survive.
我今天来这 因为你是我唯一认识的姐妹
Today I'm here because you're the only sister I've ever known.
我的结拜姐妹 一生一世
My blood sister, forever and ever.
明天 我会戴着警徽来这里
Tomorrow, I have to come back with my badge.
很高兴见到你 Stella
It's good to see you, stella.
多多保重
You take care of yourself.
Tayloe侦探!
Detective taylor!
我再也找不到她了
I'll never find her.
因为你的缘故 我再也找不到她了
Because of you, I will never find her.
拜托 先生
Please, sir.
把枪放下
Just put down the gun.
你不想这样的
You don't want to do this.
他知道她在哪儿
He knew where she was.
但你杀了他
But you killed him.
现在我再也找不到我女儿了
And now I'll never find my daughter.
街上还有无辜者
There are innocent people on the street.
只要...
Just...
把枪给我
我们可以谈谈 不管你想要什么...
just hand me the gun, and we can talk about whatever you want...
别动!
don't move!
Lily...
lily...
她看上去
和Clay Dobson杀害的其他女孩一样
she looked just like those other girls that clay dobson killed.
你相信他也带走了她
You believe he took her, too.
现在他死了 我再也找不回她了
Now that he's dead, I'll never get her back.
因为只有他知道
Because only he knows.
只有他知道把她埋在哪了
Only he knows where he buried her.
而你...
and you...
你剥夺了我的希望
you took that from me.
我再也找不回我的Lily
I'll never find my lily.
再也无法和她告别
I'll never be able to say good-bye.
我的宝贝死了
My baby's dead.